

Bogdan Plaiasu bogdan.plaiasu@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/bogdan-plaiasu

Seasoned data engineer with 12+ years of expertise in multiple areas of big data development: databases and SQL development, data warehouse solutioning and modeling, ETL development and cloud data pipelines.

I'm also experienced in web applications development.

# Skills & Qualifications

- over 12 years experience with databases
- 6+ years experience with front & backend development

### Tech Stack

- Languages: PHP, Python, Javascript, SQL
- Backend Frameworks: Django, Laravel
- Databases: MSSQL Server, MySQL, Exasol, Snowflake
- Other: Azure Data Factory (ADF), AWS S3, Airflow, Apache Spark, Databricks

### Work History

### SENIOR BIG DATA ENGINEER | COGNIZANT

02/2021 - Present

Develop a platform which collects data from multiple sources and saves the final aggregated data under one single point of truth. Based on this platform Tableau engineers were able to build useful dashboards.

- Develop and maintain Airflow dags using Python
- Writing Snowflake queries for implementing business requirements
- Create Azure Data Factory pipelines
- Migrate the existing Airflow pipelines to Databricks Workflow

Technologies used: Azure Data Factory, Spark (PySpark), Hive, AWS S3, Snowflake, Python, Airflow, Databricks

### APPLICATION DEVELOPER | AERA TECHNOLOGY

07/2019 - 02/2021

Develop an architecture for collecting multiple formats of data from different servers into one single database (an ETL)

- Set up connectors and extractions
- Work with last minute technologies like columnar databases (Exasol) and in-house ETL solution
- Create ETL's process that extract data from different ERP like SAP, Oracle, Teradata or Excel/CSV files
- Debug, improve or optimize SQL scripts ensuring that all the data is ready in minimum time; query optimization, database performance issues
- Periodical meetings with the client in order to understand the requirements
- Develop some scripts in Python & MySQL (store procedures) that are used for automation of the duplication process

Technologies used: Python, Exasol, MySQL

#### SENIOR DATA ENGINEER | SMART-X NET APPS

07/2017 - 06/2019

As a Data Engineer my role was to develop Python scripts for ETL process that extracts data from various sources. Using SQL knowhow I was able to develop, debug, optimize or improve SQL scripts to ensure that all data was ready in minimum time. Also, I had periodical meetings with the client to understand the requirements.

- Solutioning, architecting and hands-on implementing the data warehouse
- Based on the collected data along with ML team we're able to implement a fraud detection algoritm
- Create dashboards for monitoring applications (SiSense or web based)

Technologies used: MySQL, Python, PHP, SiSense, Docker, PostgreSQL, Python, Apache Spark, Hadoop, PrestoDB

### SENIOR PROGRAMMER & Team Leader | EMAG

04/2015 - 07/2017

The primary purpose of the project (eMON) was to ensure that all errors signaled in the eMag general working flux has minimal financial impact as well as minimal impact on workflow, eliminating stoppers and also ensuring that customer satisfaction is at its highest level. The project was designed for all eMag applications, and it will be a useful tool for team-leads as well as individual department members. The application through its own notification system will ensure fast delivery of error detection to all involved parties, most importantly to specialists who will be able to handle the occurred situation in a timely manner.

- Developed a database architecture based on Top-Down Approach
- Lead a team of three people

- Improve the process of bringing data (ETL) from different databases (MySQL) and at the same time managing to make this process almost "live", under 30 sec
- Together with the team we developed successful modules that were fast adopted by internal teams
- Create and maintain deployments scripts
- Analysis, design and develop new features

Technologies used: MSSQL Server, PHP

### SENIOR PROGRAMMER | HIGH-TECH SYSTEM & SOFTWARE

06/2012 - 04/2015

Improvements in code for both front & backend parts made to a customer for the retail software

Technologies used: MSSQL Server, PHP, HTML, CSS3, jQuery, Javascript

### SENIOR PROGRAMMER | SENSIBLU

03/2011 - 05/2012

I worked at the development of a new retail software for pharmacies, including the whole codebase rewriting and modernization, also creating a brand-new web interface.

- Rewrote the old logic from a Delphi software into MSSQL store procedures
- Implement the interface design

Technologies used: MSSQL Server, PHP, HTML, CSS3, jQuery, Javascript

### APPLICATION MANAGER | RELAD

06/2009 - 12/2010

Develop new business modules according to the client's needs and ongoing maintenance of the ERP software.

- Develop and maintain SQL stored procedures
- SQL queries optimization
- Web reporting

Technologies used: Charisma HR and ERP, MSSQL Server, PHP

### SQL PROGRAMMER | HELPNET FARMA

04/2008 - 06/2009

Finalizing the implementation of the CharismaHR application. Develop and implementing business requirements as provided

- Improve queries performance

- Implement business logic into SQL store procedures
- Implement reports in Crystal Reports

Technologies used: Charisma HR, MSSQL Server, PHP

### SQL PROGRAMMER | TBI CREDIT IFN

11/2007 - 04/2008

Improvements and developments in both CharismaHR & CharismaERP applications. Reports creation made in Reporting Services & Crystal Reports

Technologies used: Charisma HR and ERP, MSSQL Server, PHP

### SQL PROGRAMMER | TOTALSOFT

11/2006 - 11/2007

As a junior SQL developer my main tasks were to acquire as much knowledge as I could in a short period of time and to learn about SQL - especially MSSQL Server from Microsoft. Also I learned about a software program called CharismaHR - a tool which provides personnel data management in both terms of organizational structure and employee information.

- Comprehensive database management
- knowing CharismaHR and Crystal Reports

Technologies used: Charisma HR, Crystal Reports

### **EDUCATION**

## Polytechnic University of Bucharest

Bachelor of science, Aerospace - Degree in "Propulsion Systems and Rackets" 10/1998 - 07/2003

### PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

- PHP Certification by InfoAcademy (2011)
- Optimal Motivation by Human Invest (2016)
- Situational Leadership by Human Invest (2016)
- Essentials for Managers by Human Invest (2016)
- Exasol Essentials by Exasol (2020)
- Hands On Essentials Data Warehouse by Snowflake (2021)
- Developer Foundation Databricks (2021)